-是  -好的
- Yep. - OK.
你曾告诉我杀人
You told me that killing someone
是这世界上最丑恶的事
was the ugliest thing in the world.
最丑恶的事之一
One of them.
我终于明白了
I finally get it.
我觉得我有问题
I thought there was something wrong with me
我杀尼克・博伊尔时一点也没有厌恶感
because I didn't feel ugly when I killed Nick Boyle.
我感觉很好
I felt good.
所以撒起谎来也容易
That's why it was so easy to lie about it.
感觉像你没做错任何事
Like you didn't do anything wrong.
你杀我爸爸的时候感觉自己做错了吗
Feel like you'd done something wrong when you killed my dad?
我吓坏了
I felt terrified.
然后
And then...
我感到充满力量
I felt powerful.
当你终于结束它
It felt good...
终结这一切  那种感觉很好
to get to end it, to stop it all.
我以为我已经摆脱他了
I thought I got away from him.
我想我们俩都未曾摆脱你父亲
I don't think either of us have gotten away from your father.
我好希望我杀了他
I wish I'd killed him.
为我妈妈的死
For killing my mom,
为那些女孩的死  为他把我...
for killing all those girls, for making me...
把你怎么了  阿比盖尔
Making you what, Abigail?
把我卷入其中
Part of it.
卷入这所有的事
Part of any of it.
我的生活不该变成这样
This wasn't supposed to be my life.
感觉就像我爸爸还在这里
It feels like my dad's still out there.
从某种意义上说  他的确还在
In a way, he is.
你是说那个模仿犯
You mean the copycat.
我觉得我能抓到他
I think I can catch him.
但我需要你的帮助
But I'm gonna need your help.
一位FBI探员来找过我
An agent from the FBI came to see me.
他向我了解你和威尔・格雷厄姆的关系
He asked me questions about your relationship with Will Graham.
杰克・克劳福德来过了
Jack Crawford was here?
对于你告诉他的
He had enough doubt
关于你的病人的事  他有许多疑虑
in whatever it is you told him about your patient
需要得到证实
to feel the need to verify.
他认为阿比盖尔・霍布斯是她父亲的帮凶
He believes Abigail Hobbs was involved in her father's crimes,
并怀疑威尔在保护她
and he suspects Will is protecting her.
很显然他还怀疑你在保护威尔
And evidently he suspects you are protecting Will.
你是吗
Are you?
你是作为我的心理医生问我吗
Are you asking as my psychiatrist?
走出作为你心理医生的身份
I'm stepping out of my role as your psychiatrist
现在我作为同事与你交谈
and I'm speaking to you now as your colleague.
不管你在对威尔・格雷厄姆做什么
Whatever you're doing with Will Graham,
停下
stop.
威尔需要我的帮助
Will needs my help.
你已经越界了
You've crossed professional lines.
交个朋友就是越界吗
By making a friend?
【求校对】你不能代表对方来与自己建立友谊
You cannot function as an agent of friendship
【求校对】尤其是他对你的行为毫不知情
for a man who is disconnected from the concept
【求校对】你这样做是假装自己不知情
as a man who is disconnected from the concept.
我在保护威尔免受影响
I'm protecting Will from influence.
对于他为何成为这样这个问题
He has flaws in his intuitive beliefs about
他的直觉有误
what makes him who he is.
我在试图让他理解
I'm trying to help him understand.
也许你做不到
You may not be able to.
【求校对】我不愿告诉威尔我对他的极力帮助
I'm not comfortable telling Will
【求校对】可能是无效的  也不愿告诉他
that my very best attempts to help him may fail
【求校对】我对他的忠实和治疗
and that my loyalty to him
【求校对】会受到威胁
and his treatment could be compromised.
那就告诉他别的
Then tell him something else.
克劳福德探员还问了我我遇袭的事
Agent Crawford also asked me about my attack.
了然
I see.
你怎么说的
What did you tell him?
真假参半
Half-truths.
我告诉他一个暴力的病人
That a violent patient
在袭击我的时候  又改变主意了
swallowed his tongue while he was attacking me.
我没说过程和原因
I didn't tell him how or why
没说是谁
or who was responsible.
你在杰克・克劳福德面前保护自己的病人
You protect your patient from Jack Crawford,
而我就不能
but I can't protect mine.
【求校对】是不能继续
Not anymore.
即使是最顶尖的心理医生
Even the very best psychiatrists
在专业能力上也有其无力之处
have an inherent limitation to their professional abilities.
或许这对你很难接受
You may find that difficult to accept.
对  的确很难接受
You're right. It is.
你必须保持距离  汉尼拔
You have to maintain boundaries, Hannibal.
当我和威尔的私人和医患关系
When the pressures of my personal and professional relationships
造成的压力变得不可承受时
with Will grow too great,
我向你保证...
I assure you...
那时我想办法释放压力的
I'll find a way to relieve them.